Finding Aid for the Los Angeles Unified School District Architect's Renderings and Campus Photographs LSC.2394
UCLA Library Special Collections
Los Angeles Unified School District Architect's Renderings and Campus Photographs
1913-1987
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.2394
0.4 linear feet (1 document box)
This collection includes photographs and architect's renderings of Los Angeles Unified School District campuses and other materials related to construction including blueprints.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Alan Rubin, Los Angeles Unified School District, July 2013.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9988584463606533
History
According to the Los Angeles Unified School District Board of Education Records, as a result of the school unification election of June 7, 1960, the LAUSD formed on July 1, 1961 from the Los Angeles City School District and the Los Angeles City High School District. The District encompasses approximately 710 square miles, includes virtually all of the City of Los Angeles, many other cities and several unincorporated areas of Los Angeles County. The LAUSD is the largest public school system in California based on pupil enrollment and the second largest public school district in the United States. For more information, see the Los Angeles Unified School District Board of Education records (Collection 1923).
Scope and Content
This collection includes architect's renderings and photographs of elementary, middle, and high school campuses. It also includes: an architecture firm-produced booklet of photographs of a middle school; photographs of pilot training; and papers regarding construction, including blueprints, a construction inspector's diary, and correspondence regarding the purchase of a fountain. Some schools included are no longer part of the LAUSD and some schools now operate under different names.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection is organized alphabetically by historic school name.
Related Material
Los Angeles Unified School District Board of Education records (Collection Number 1923). Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
- Alfred Bernard Nobel Junior High, 1963 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Birmingham Jr. High School, Brainard, and Broad Ave. School., Ca. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Broadacres Ave., Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Broadway School, Brockton Avenue School, Buchanan Avenue School, Budlong Ave. Elementary School, Burnside Avenue School, Dodson Junior High, 1913 and later (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Donna Avenue School: Blueprint, 1961 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Fishburn Avenue School, Francisco Sepulveda Junior High, and Gates Street School, 1961-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Gulf Avenue School, Haddon Avenue School, Hale Junior High, and Harbor City School, 1923-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- John Muir Junior High and Joseph Pomeroy Widney High School, 1936 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Kester Avenue, 1956 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Liberty Blvd. School: Construction Inspector's Diary, 1936 July 6 - 1937 January 21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mount Vernon Junior High, Mt. Washington Elementary, and Mt. Gleason Junior High, 1926-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mulholland Junior High School: Booklet of photographs made by architecture firm, 1963 November (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Murchison Street School and Napa St. School, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Narbonne High School: Blueprint, photograph, and correspondence regarding purchase of a fountain, 1929 March 18 - 1929 April 9 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Normandie Avenue School, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Normont School, N. Hollywood Junior High, O'Melveny, Palos Verdes High School, and Riggin Avenue School, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- San Fernando Junior High, San Pascual Ave. School, San Pedro High, Santa Monica Blvd. School, and Saturn Street School, 1924 and later (Box 1, Folder 17)
- School for Handicapped, Seventh St. Elementary, Seventy-Fifth Street School, Sharp Ave. School, and South of Granada Junior High (Nobel Junior High), 1922-1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Wilmington Park, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Los Angeles City College Pilot Training Unit, 1942 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)